sifted.eu 2019-12-10

# Privacy Policy | Sifted

  *   *  
  * 

The new-media platform for Europe's innovators and entrepreneurs

* * *

  *   *   *   *   *   * 

SIFTED (EU) LIMITED, of 20-22 WENLOCK RD, London, England, N1 7GU (company no. 11080313), (the “ **Company** ” “ **We** “, “ **Us** ” and “ **Our** ”) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our [Terms and Conditions of Business](https://sifted.eu/terms-of-use/), [Terms of Website Use](https://sifted.eu/terms-of-use/#terms), [Cookie Policy](https://sifted.eu/terms-of-use/#cookies) and [Acceptable Use Policy](https://sifted.eu/terms-of-use/#acceptable-use) which can be accessed on www.sifted.eu and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting www.sifted.eu ( **our Site** ) you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the **Act** ), the data controller is the Company.

#### Information we may collect from you

We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * **Information you give us**. You may give us information about you by filling in forms on our Site or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register to use our Site, subscribe to our service, arrange a booking at an event or place an advertisement on our Site, participate in comment or discussion boards or other social media functions on our Site, enter a competition, promotion or survey, report a problem with our Site, and any other activities commonly carried out on our Site. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address, phone number, date of birth/age, gender, financial and credit card information, personal description, photographs or avatars, relationship information and other preferences that you state in relation to the service we offer, as well as any information you give us about the business in which you work.
  * **Information we collect about you**. With regard to each of your visits to our Site we may automatically collect the following information: 
    * technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform;
    * information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our Site (including date and time); articles, services or products you viewed or searched for; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our customer service number.
  * **Information we receive from other sources**. We may receive information about you if you use any other websites we operate or other services we provide. We are also working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them.

#### Cookie Policy

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our Site. By continuing to browse the Site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies, explained as follows.

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive.

We use the following cookies:

  * **Strictly necessary cookies**. These are cookies that are required for the operation of our Site. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our Site, arrange and manage bookings and make use of e-billing services.
  * **Analytical/performance cookies**. These allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our Site when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our Site works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.
  * **Functionality cookies**. These are used to recognise you when you return to our Site. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your favourite choice of service).
  * **Targeting cookies**. These cookies record your visit to our Site, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our Site and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

We may place our cookies on your device via our Site. Accordingly, our Privacy Policy will apply to our treatment of the information we obtain via our cookies.

We may also allow our business partners to place cookies on your device. For example, we use Google Analytics for web analytics, and so Google may also set cookies on your device. As further explained below, third parties may also place cookies on your device for advertising purposes.

There are two types of cookies used on our Site, namely “persistent cookies” and “session cookies”.

Session cookies will normally expire when you close your browser, while persistent cookies will remain on your device after you close your browser, and can be used again the next time you access our Site.

Our Site may also use other technologies with similar functionality to cookies, such as web beacons and tracking URLs to obtain Log Data about users. We may also use web beacons and tracking URLs in our messages to you to determine whether you have opened a certain message or accessed a certain link.

Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.

You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our Site.

We can change this Cookie Policy at any time. If we make material changes to the Cookie Policy, we will let you know either by posting the changed Cookie Policy on our Site or by sending you an email.

It’s important that you review the changed Cookie Policy. If you do not wish to agree to the changed Cookie Policy, then we cannot continue to provide our Site to you, and your only option is to stop accessing our Site and deactivate your account.

#### Uses made of the information

We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * **Information you give to us**. We will use this information: 
    * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us;
    * to provide you with information about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about;
    * to provide you, or permit selected third parties to provide you, with information about goods or services we feel may interest you. If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale or negotiations of a sale to you. If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this. If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data (the registration and/or booking forms);
    * to notify you about changes to our service and significant changes to our terms of use and service;
    * to ensure that content from our Site is presented in the most effective manner to you.
  * **Information we collect about you**. We will use this information: 
    * to administer our Site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
    * to improve our Site to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
    * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;
    * as part of our efforts to keep our Site safe and secure;
    * to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you;
    * to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Site about goods or services that may interest you or them.
  * **Information we receive from other sources**. We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may use this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).
  * **Google Analytics** : The cookies in use on our website include cookies for Google Analytics. Like many services, Google Analytics uses first-party cookies to collect information to enable us to understand how visitors engage with our site. You can access more information about the cookies used by Google Analytics click here.

The Google Analytics features we use are userID and demographics and interest reporting, which means that we may collect information about your computer or device, including your IP address, operating system and browser type; the date and time you visited our site; whether you have visited our site before; the site that referred you to our site; and your age, gender, and interests.

We then use the information for system administration and to compile reports which include statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns, to help us improve our site. The information collected by Google Analytics is collected anonymously and reports website trends without identifying individual visitors. You can opt out of Google Analytics without affecting how you visit our site [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

#### Disclosure of your information

We may share your personal information with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may share your information with selected third parties including:

  * Business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you.
  * Advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others. We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users (for example, we may inform them that 500 men aged under 30 have clicked on their advertisement on any given day). We may also use such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target (for example, women in SW3). We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers’ wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience.
  * Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our Site.
  * Credit reference agencies for the purpose of assessing your credit score where this is a condition of us entering into a contract with you.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If we or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, personal data held by us about our customers may be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms and Conditions and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of the Company, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

#### Where we store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Site, you are responsible for keeping that password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

#### Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at Sifted c/o Second Home, Clerkenwell House, Clerkenwell Green, London EC1R 0EB or [hello@sifted.eu](mailto:hello@sifted.eu).

Our Site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

#### Access to information

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

#### Changes to our Privacy Policy

Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our Privacy Policy.

#### Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to Sifted, c/o Second Home, Clerkenwell House, Clerkenwell Green, London EC1R 0EB or [hello@sifted.eu](mailto:hello@sifted.eu).
